Nirenstein National Realty Map Company Records
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Nirenstein National Realty Map Company Records.
undated, 1909-1983.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center
Nirenstein National Realty Map Company.
28 linear feet.
The Nirenstein National Realty Map Company of Springfield, Massachusetts, produced high quality atlases of urban and suburban businesses and shopping centers. Nathan Nirenstein founded the company in 1925.
MSS19880039
History
The Nirenstein National Realty Map Company of Springfield, Massachusetts, produced high quality atlases of urban and suburban businesses and shopping centers. Nathan Nirenstein, who founded the company in 1925, was born in Russia in 1890 and immigrated to the United States in early 1900s. Before creating the atlas company, he was involved in the real estate business in the Springfield, Massachusetts, area. The company published atlases for New England, the Middle Atlantic States, New York City, Pennsylvania, Virginia, West Virginia and the Southern states.
Nathan Nirenstein was also a prominent realtor and developer in the city of Springfield, where he owned and operated the Kellogg Building Realty Trust Company. The company had two subordinate operations, the Harrison Realty Company and Bowles Lunch, Inc. He personally operated both the atlas company and the real estate company until shortly before his death in 1973 at the age of 83. His businesses were taken over by his son, David Joel Nirenstein.
Although Nirenstein's National Realty Map Company discontinued its production of updated maps in 1958, an inventory of historically important maps remained. These maps were sold to libraries and historical societies throughout the United States and Canada, until the company was finally disbanded in the 1980s.
Scope and Content
The collection contains administrative and financial records for the map and realty companies dating from 1909 through 1983.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Records (undated, 1918-1983 ) contains personal papers and business records of Nathan Nirenstein and David Joel Nirenstein. Subseries A holds the personal and professional papers of Nathan Nirenstein, including correspondence and speeches, arranged chronologically. Subseries B holds Nathan Nirenstein's diaries and telephone and address books. Subseries C holds the personal and professional correspondence of David Joel Nirenstein, organized alphabetically.
Series II: Map Company Records (undated, 1924-1974 ) contains sales records and correspondence of the atlas company. These records are divided into the following categories: General, National Atlas, New England Atlas, New York City Atlas, Mid-Atlantic States Atlas, Pennsylvania and Virginia Atlas, Deep South Atlas, and Central States Atlas. Also included are tenant brochures, which held correspondence and other materials about commercial properties to be included in the atlases.
Series III: Realty Records ( undated, 1914-1980 ) contains the general records of the Kellogg Building Realty Trust Company. The realty company was organized before and was managed separately from the atlas company, but it was run out of the same office in Springfield, Massachusetts. The realty company also had two subordinate operations, the Harrison Realty Company and Bowles Lunch, Inc. The series contains two categories of records: Realty Correspondence and Realty Legal Documents.
Series IV: Financial Records ( 1909-1983 ) contains the general accounting records of both the atlas company and the realty company, including the subordinate operations of the Harrison Realty Company and Bowles Lunch, Inc. Types of records include financial statements, ledgers, journals, a payroll book, and rental records.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England and Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Nirenstein, Nathan--Correspondence.
Organizations:
Nirenstein National Realty Map Company.; Kellogg Building Realty Trust Company.; Harrison Realty Trust Company.; Bowles Lunch, Inc.
Subjects:
Cartographers--History--Sources.; Cartographers--Massachusetts--Springfield.; Cities and towns--United States.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The Nirenstein National Realty Map Company donated its records and a selection of its atlases and maps to the University of Connecticut Map Library in October 1988. The business records were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives (now Archives & Special Collections) shortly afterwards.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Administrative Records, undated, 1918-1983
  - Subseries A: Nathan Nirenstein's Papers, undated, 1918-1973
    - Map company incorporation papers, 1928-1935 (Box 1:1)
    - Photograph of Nathan Nirenstein, undated (Box 1:2)
    - Rough drafts of speeches and correspondence to prospective publishers, 1941-1949 (Box 1:3)
    - Address to the New Haven Real Estate Board address, 1947 (Box 1:4)
    - Correspondence, Public Relations, 1947-1949 (Box 1:5)
    - "Build for Peace" brochure and related correspondence, 1948 (Box 1:6)
    - Commissioner of Corporation and Taxes, 1948-1950 (Box 1:7)
    - "Rent Control, The Bane of Building" article, 1948-1949 (Box 1:8)
    - Collins, Russell, 1948 (Box 1:9)
    - Kobler, John, 1949-1954 (Box 1:10)
    - Stockbrokers, 1949-1959 (Box 1:11)
    - Dwight Street controversy, 1951-1952 (Box 1:12)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1951 (Box 1:13)
    - Time and Fortune, 1951-1955 (Box 1:14)
    - Architectural Forum, 1953 (Box 1:15)
    - Coronet, 1953 (Box 1:16)
    - Speech, "Is Main Street on Trial?" with correspondence and brochures, 1953 (Box 1:17)
    - Massachusetts Real Estate Association, 1953-54 (Box 1:18)
    - "What I Observed in El Paso, Los Angeles, San Francisco and Los[sic] Vegas," speech given at the N.A.R.E.B. convention in Los Angeles, 1953 (Box 1:19)
    - The New Yorker, 1953 (Box 1:20)
    - Providence Journal, 1953 (Box 1:21)
    - Requests for speeches and articles, 1953-1955 (Box 1:22)
    - Boston Herald, 1954 (Box 1:23)
    - Clark, Willard, 1954 (Box 1:24)
    - Complimentary copies of speeches, 1954-1955 (Box 1:25)
    - National Association of Assessing Officers, 1954 (Box 1:26)
    - Proposed Real Estate College, 1954-1955 (Box 1:27)
    - Taylor, George R., 1954-1958 (Box 1:28)
    - West Harwich, Massachusetts, Speech, 1954 (Box 1:29)
    - Article and correspondence about "The Realtor in the 20th Century," given at the New England Realtors Convention in Manchester, Vermont, 1955-1957 (Box 1:30)
    - Vermont speech, 1955 (Box 1:31)
    - Boston speech, 1956 (Box 1:32)
    - Department of Corporations and Taxes, 1956 (Box 1:33)
    - "Man - The Builder" speech, 1956-1964 (Box 1:34)
    - National Association of Realtors, 1956 (Box 1:35)
    - "Rejected Firms Defend Two Bids on Revaluing," 1956 (Box 1:36)
    - Report on the 1956 Real Estate Convention in St. Louis, Missouri, 1956 (Box 1:37)
    - Economic History Association, 1957 (Box 1:38)
    - Federal Reserve System, 1957 (Box 1:39)
    - Linnell, Al, 1957 (Box 1:40)
    - Goodman, Percival, 1958 (Box 1:41)
    - Railroad articles and correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1:42)
    - Reader's Digest, 1958 (Box 1:43)
    - Ross, Stanley C., 1958 (Box 1:44)
    - Speech before the Sojourners' Club at Westover Air Force Base, Chicopee Falls, Masschusetts, 1958 (Box 1:45)
    - "Our National Tax Problems," address given at the New England Realtors Convention in Manchester, Vermont, 1958 (Box 1:46)
    - Passenger Rail Service, 1959 (Box 1:47)
    - Whyman, Herbert, 1959 (Box 1:48)
    - Massachusetts Assessors speech, 1960-1961 (Box 1:49)
    - "Let Us be Kind to Our City Employees" article, 1961 (Box 1:50)
    - "Downtown: the Appraiser's Dilemma", 1961-1962 (Box 1:51)
    - "Springfield Is Becoming a City of Old Buildings, 1961 (Box 1:52)
    - "Tax Relief - Where?" article, 1961 (Box 1:53)
    - Westover Air Force Base Speech, 1961 (Box 1:54)
    - "Israel and the Mediterranean" article, 1962 (Box 1:55)
    - Taylor, George R., 1962 (Box 1:56)
    - Nelson, James, 1965 (Box 1:57)
    - Proposed merger with Sanborn Map Company, 1968 (Box 1:58)
    - Drafts of various articles and speeches, undated (Box 1:59)
    - Probus Club speech, undated (Box 1:60)
    - Untitled speech about the valuation of property in Springfield, Massachusetts, undated (Box 1:61)
  - Subseries B: Nathan Nirenstein's Diaries and Address and Telephone Books, undated, 1950-1974
    - Diaries (8 volumes), 1950-1974 (Box 2)
    - Diaries (15 volumes), 1958-1974 (Box 3)
    - Address and telephone books, undated (Box 3)
  - Subseries C: David Joel Nirenstein's Writings and Correspondence, 1975-1983
    - A, 1975-1980 (Box 2:62)
    - B-C, 1975-1980 (Box 2:63)
    - Canada, 1977-1982 (Box 2:64)
    - D, 1976-1977 (Box 2:65)
    - F, 1975-1978 (Box 2:66)
    - L, 1975-1983 (Box 2:67)
    - M, 1975-1983 (Box 2:68)
    - N, 1975-1982 (Box 2:69)
    - O, 1976-1978 (Box 2:70)
    - P, 1975-1983 (Box 2:71)
    - R, 1975-1982 (Box 2:72)
    - S, 1976-1981 (Box 2:73)
    - T, 1975-1983 (Box 2:74)
    - V, 1974-1980 (Box 2:75)
    - W-Z, 1976-1978 (Box 2:76)
    - Foreign archives, 1979 (Box 2:77)
- Series II: Map Company Records,undated, 1924-1974
  - General Sales and Correspondence
    - Aetna Life Insurance, 1954-1955 (Box 4:78)
    - Alameda Free Library, 1955 (Box 4:79)
    - Allied Sales Corporation, 1955 (Box 4:80)
    - American Appraisal Company, 1955 (Box 4:81)
    - Anglo-Californian National Bank, 1955 (Box 4:82)
    - Architecture and urban planning, Seattle, Washington, 1958 (Box 4:83)
    - Armstrong Associates, 1954-1955 (Box 4:84)
    - Banker's Life Insurance, 1954-1955 (Box 4:85)
    - Bickford Life Insurance, 1955 (Box 4:86)
    - Bids for publishing new atlas, 1954 (Box 4:87)
    - Brooklyn Public Library, 1954-1955 (Box 4:88)
    - Brooks, Harvey and Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:89)
    - Chambers of commerce, 1951-1953 (Box 4:90)
    - Springfield Library Association, 1958 (Box 4:91)
    - California State Library, 1962 (Box 4:92)
    - Coldwell, Banker and Company, 1955-1958 (Box 4:93)
    - Connecticut General Life Insurance, 1954-1955 (Box 4:94)
    - Continental Service Company, 1955 (Box 4:95)
    - Cornell University, 1958-1959 (Box 4:96)
    - Crocker First National Bank of San Francisco, 1955 (Box 4:97)
    - Draper Companies of San Francisco, California, 1961-1962 (Box 4:98)
    - Dreyfus Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:99)
    - E.M. Simon Company, 1955 (Box 4:100)
    - Enterprise Records, 1955 (Box 4:101)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1955-1958 (Box 4:102)
    - Four Continent Book Corporation, 1958 (Box 4:103)
    - Franklin Life Insurance Corporation, 1955 (Box 4:104)
    - Franklin Stores Corporation, 1955 (Box 4:105)
    - G.R. Kinney Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:106)
    - Gallenkamp Stores Company, 1955 (Box 4:107)
    - General Services Administration, 1957 (Box 4:108)
    - Glickman, Louis, 1953-1955 (Box 4:109)
    - Godfrey, Paul, 1955 (Box 4:110)
    - Harry Shandling and Sons Company, 1955 (Box 4:111)
    - Heymann and Brothers, 1955 (Box 4:112)
    - Hubbard, Westervelt & Mottelay, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 4:113)
    - Illinois State Library, 1954-1958 (Box 4:114)
    - J. Halperin Company, 1965 (Box 4:115)
    - John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:116)
    - Kansas City Life Insurance Company, 1955 (Box 4:117)
    - Karesh, Eleanor R., 1955 (Box 4:118)
    - Lerner Shops, 1954-1956 (Box 4:119)
    - Library of Congress, 1955-1958 (Box 4:120)
    - Liles, Robert, 1961 (Box 4:121)
    - Lionel Wachs Company, 1956 (Box 4:122)
    - Los Angeles Public Library, 1954-1961 (Box 4:123)
    - Lurie Company, 1958 (Box 4:124)
    - Lyon Company, 1955 (Box 4:125)
    - Mapes, C. Warren, 1955 (Box 4:126)
    - Marble Mortgage Company, 1958 (Box 4:127)
    - Martel, Jules, 1955 (Box 4:128)
    - Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance, 1955 (Box 4:129)
    - McKeegan, Edward, 1955 (Box 4:130)
    - Metcalf Enterprises, 1959-1960 (Box 4:131)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:132)
    - Meyer Schwartz Company, 1956-1957 (Box 4:133)
    - Miller, Harvey, 1955 (Box 4:134)
    - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance, 1954-1955 (Box 4:135)
    - N.M. Saunders Company, 1955 (Box 4:136)
    - National Life & Accident Insurance Company, 1955 (Box 4:137)
    - New England Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:138)
    - New York Life Insurance Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:139)
    - New York Public Library, 1954-1961 (Box 4:140)
    - Newspaper press releases, 1954-1955 (Box 4:141)
    - Norris, Beggs & Simpson, 1954-1955 (Box 4:142)
    - Northwestern Mutual Life Insturance Company of Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1955 (Box 4:143)
    - Oakland Real Estate Board, 1957 (Box 4:144)
    - Phoenix Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1955 (Box 4:145)
    - Prudential Life Insurance Company, 1955-1958 (Box 4:146)
    - R.A. Rowan & Company, 1957-1962 (Box 4:147)
    - Ray C. Seeley Company, 1955-1957 (Box 4:148)
    - Rea, Philip M., 1956-1957 (Box 4:149)
    - Regal Shoe Manufacturing Company, 1955 (Box 4:150)
    - Roy Wenzick & Company, 1954-1955 (Box 4:151)
    - S. H. Kress & Company, 1955 (Box 4:152)
    - St. George Holden Company, 1956 (Box 4:153)
    - San Francisco Public Library, 1955 (Box 4:154)
    - Santa Barbara Public Library, 1955 (Box 4:155)
    - Shattuck, Charles B., 1955 (Box 4:156)
    - Simon, Bert, 1955 (Box 4:157)
    - Sperry & Hutchinson Company, 1955 (Box 4:158)
    - State Mutual life Insurance Company, 1954-1957 (Box 4:159)
    - Student placement bureaus, 1955 (Box 4:160)
    - Swig, Benjamin, 1955 (Box 4:161)
    - Teacher's Insurance & Annuity Association, 1954-1955 (Box 4:162)
    - Travelers Insurance Company, Los Angeles, California, 1955 (Box 4:163)
    - Travelers Insurance Company, Hartford, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 4:164)
    - Turner's Investments, 1960 (Box 4:165)
    - U. Ernest Nelson & Associates, 1948-1950 (Box 4:166)
    - United States Post Office Department, 1954-1955 (Box 4:167)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1957-1958 (Box 4:168)
    - University of Illinois, 1958 (Box 4:169)
    - Vought, Ward & Nichols, 1955 (Box 4:170)
    - Wells Fargo Bank, 1955 (Box 4:171)
    - Western New England College, 1958 (Box 4:172)
    - White, C.H. (salesman), 1954-1955 (Box 4:173)
    - Wolcott, Henry, 1954-1955 (Box 4:174)
    - Arizona inquiries, 1954-1959 (Box 4:175)
    - Arizona sales, 1954-1955 (Box 4:176)
    - California inquiries, A - M, 1954-1974 (Box 4:177)
    - California inquiries, N - Z, 1954-1962 (Box 4:178)
    - California single chart sales, 1955 (Box 4:179)
    - Clockings for new atlas, undated (Box 4:180)
    - Colorado inquiries, 1954-1959 (Box 4:181)
    - Hawaii inquiries, 1955-1961 (Box 4:182)
    - Idaho inquiries, 1954-1961 (Box 4:183)
    - Iowa inquiries, 1955 (Box 4:184)
    - Montana inquiries, 1955-1958 (Box 4:185)
    - Nevada inquiries, 1954-1959 (Box 4:186)
    - New Mexico inquiries, 1957-1963 (Box 4:187)
    - Oregon inquiries, 1954-1961 (Box 4:188)
    - Utah inquiries, 19545-1959 (Box 4:189)
    - Washington [state] inquiries, 1954-1961 (Box 4:190)
    - Wyoming inquiries, 1954 (Box 4:191)
    - Inquiries from other states (except for those listed above), 1954-1963 (Box 4:192)
    - Sales for western United States single charts, 1955-1959 (Box 4:193)
    - Colorado single chart sales, 1955 (Box 4:194)
    - Hawaii single chart sales, 1955-1958 (Box 4:195)
    - Idaho single chart sales, 1954-1955 (Box 4:196)
    - Montana single chart sales, 1955 (Box 4:197)
    - Nevada single chart sales, 1954-1955 (Box 4:198)
    - New Mexico single chart sales, 1955 (Box 4:199)
    - Oregon single chart sales, 1954-1959 (Box 5:200)
    - Utah single chart sales, 1954-1959 (Box 5:201)
    - Washington [state] single chart sales, 1955-1962 (Box 5:202)
    - Wyoming single chart sales, 1955-1959 (Box 5:203)
  - National Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Cobb, Beasley & Miles, 1924-1930 (Box 5:204)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by city, A - Z, 1924-1960 (Box 5:205-307)
    - Library inquiries, 1951 (Box 5:308)
    - General national inquiries, 1946-1952 (Box 5:309)
    - National atlas, single charts, 1950-1955 (Box 5:310)
    - Unfinished business, 1952-1953 (Box 5:311)
  - New England Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Clocking, Photographs and aerial views, undated (Box 5:312)
    - Complimentary maps for assessors, 1945-1960 (Box 5:313)
    - General inquiries, 1945-1950 (Box 5:314)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by city, 1945-1960
      - A - B (Box 5:315-319)
      - C - Z (Box 6:320-358)
    - Maps sent to banks, 1947 (Box 6:359)
    - Maps to be sent to Danbury, Connecticut, 1947-1949 (Box 6:360)
    - Maps to be sent to Springfield, Massachusetts, 1947-1949 (Box 6:361)
    - Inquiries, 1951-1953 (Box 6:362)
    - Single chart requests A - Z, by customer, 1945-1960 (Box 6:363-364)
    - Parker Webb, map of Springfield, Massachusetts, 1955 (Box 6:365)
    - Snelling Company correspondence, 1952 (Box 6:366)
    - Unfinished business, 1949-1953 (Box 6:367)
  - New York City Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Aerial views: Canadian correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 6:368)
    - Architects: shopping centers, 1957 (Box 6:369)
    - Canadian atlas: W. Warwick, Eng., 1955-1956 (Box 6:370)
    - Canadian decentralized shopping centers, 1955-1956 (Box 6:371)
    - Canadian single chart requests, 1955-1958 (Box 6:372)
    - Chambers of Commerce: Canada and Florida, 1955-1956 (Box 6:373)
    - Clockings for New York City atlas, 1956 (Box 6:374)
    - Engineers letters: Canada, 1954-1957 (Box 6:375)
    - General sales and correspondence, A - Z, by customer name, 1955-1961
      - A - N (Box 6:376-387)
      - P - Z (Box 7:388-395)
    - Herald Tribune write-up, 1956 (Box 7:396)
    - Hurst Engineering: Canada, 1955 (Box 7:397)
    - London Times map article, 1955 (Box 7:398)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 7:399)
    - New York City business, 1956 (Box 7:400)
    - New York City convention, 1955-1960 (Box 7:401)
    - New York City Stock exchange information, 1956 (Box 7:402)
    - New York City tax reports, 1956 (Box 7:403)
    - New York Times, "Our Changing City" article, 1956 (Box 7:404)
    - Ottawa, Canada contract, 1957-1958 (Box 7:405)
    - Photograph correspondence, 1955 (Box 7:406)
    - Principal Investments Ltd., 1955 (Box 7:407)
    - Real Estate Board banquet information, 1956 (Box 7:408)
    - Saint John, New Brunswick, Canada correspondence, 1955 (Box 7:409)
    - Single chart requests, 1955-1960 (Box 7:410)
    - Shopping center inquiries, 1956-1958 (Box 7:411)
    - Tax Commission report, 1960 (Box 7:412)
  - Mid-Atlantic Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Brochures sent, 1951-1953 (Box 7:413)
    - Chambers of Commerce: New Jersey and New York, 1946 (Box 7:414)
    - Clockings and aerial views, undated (Box 7:415)
    - General inquiries, listed by customer, 1945-1952
      - A - Z (Box 7:416-426)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by city, 1945-1960
      - Albany, New York - New York, New York (Box 7:427-457)
      - New York, New York - Yonkers, New York (Box 8:458-474)
    - New Jersey Turnpike information, undated (Box 8:475)
    - New York State Library, 1947-1949 (Box 8:476)
    - Single chart orders, listed by customer
      - A - Z (Box 8:477-484)
    - Special inquiries, 1951-1955 (Box 8:485)
    - Unfinished business, 1945-1955 (Box 8:486)
  - Pennsylvania and Virginia Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Atlas contracts, general, 1945-1947 (Box 8:487)
    - Atlas contracts, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8:488)
    - Atlas inventory and corrections, 1946-1953 (Box 8:489)
    - Busansky, Sheldon sales accounts, 1950-1955 (Box 8:490)
    - Chambers of Commerce correspondence, 1952 (Box 8:491-492)
    - Clockings, aerial views, and photographs, 1947-1950 (Box 8:493)
    - Complimentary atlases for libraries, 1948 (Box 8:494)
    - Degenhardt Agency correspondence, 1952 (Box 8:495)
    - Foreign library correspondence, 1953 (Box 8:496)
    - General inquiries, listed by customer, 1947-1954
      - A - Z (Box 8:497-498)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by city, 1945-1955
      - A - N (Box 8:499-509)
      - N - Z (Box 9:510-517)
    - Inquiries to life insurance companies, 1950 (Box 9:518-519)
    - Libraries, 1953-1954 (Box 9:520)
    - Maps sent to mortgage loan companies (Box 9:521)
    - Mortgage loan companies correspondence, 1953 (Box 9:522)
    - Newspaper write-ups, 1949 (Box 9:523)
    - Pennsylvania and Virginia inquiries, 1952-1954 (Box 9:524-525)
    - Philadelphia inquiries, 1949-1958 (Box 9:526)
    - Public and state libraries, 1945-1950 (Box 9:527-528)
    - R.L. Polk Company correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 9:529)
    - R.L. Polk Company orders received, 1953 (Box 9:530)
    - Rachelson, Melvin, 1955 (Box 9:531)
    - Real Estate Boards, 1953 (Box 9:532)
    - Salesman correspondence, 1949 (Box 9:533)
    - Savings bank correspondence, 1950 (Box 9:534)
    - Sherrill, Sherrill and Company, 1950 (Box 9:535)
    - Single chart inquiries, listed by customer name, 1945-1960
      - A - Z (Box 9:536-543)
    - Single chart returns, 1950 (Box 9:544)
    - Single chart subscribers, 1953 (Box 9:545)
    - Unfinished business, 1950-1956 (Box 9:546)
  - Deep South Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Atlas inquiries, 1950-1960 (Box 9:547-549)
    - Clockings, aerial views, and photographs, 1955 (Box 9:550)
    - Complaints, 1951 (Box 9:551)
    - General correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 9:552)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by customer, 1945-1955
      - A - G (Box 9:553-559)
      - H - Z (Box 10:560-572)
    - Mayor of Savannah, Georgia, correspondence, 1955 (Box 10:573)
    - Port of Houston, Texas, correspondence, 1951 (Box 10:574)
    - Single chart sales, listed by customer, 1945-1961
      - A - Z (Box 10:575-595)
    - Unfinished business, 1950-1960 (Box 10:596)
  - Central States Atlas Sales and Correspondence
    - Atlas Information, 1950-1953 (Box 11:597)
    - Clockings, 1952 (Box 11:598)
    - Corrections and errors, 1952 (Box 11:599)
    - Engineer's correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 11:600)
    - Inquiries A - Z, 1947-1962 (Box 11:601-613)
    - General sales and correspondence, listed by city, 1950-1965
      - A - Z (Box 11:614-656)
    - Single chart sales, listed by states, 1950-1965
      - A - M (Box 11:657-668)
      - M - W (Box 12:669-679)
  - Tenant Brochures
    - Brochures, listed by city
      - A - S, 1957-1961 (Box 13:680-755)
      - S - Z, 1956-1961 (Box 14:756-777)
    - Oversized brochures
      - Cincinnati, Ohio (Box 15:778)
      - Eatontown, New Jersy (Box 15:779)
      - Los Angeles, California (Box 15:780)
      - Tucson, Arizona (Box 15:781)
- Series III: Realty Records, undated, 1914-1980
  [Unless otherwise noted all properties are located in the Springfield, Massachusetts, area.]
  - Realty Correspondence
    - Crescent Hill property, correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 16:782)
    - Crescent Hill property, documents, 1962-1970 (Box 16:783)
    - Kellogg Building Realty Trust accounts, 1971 (Box 16:784)
    - Estate matters, 1973-1980 (Box 16:785)
    - Trust agreement, 1968-1970 (Box 16:786)
    - 1305 Main Street property, 1952-1962 (Box 16:787)
    - Bowles, Francis T. correspondence, 1961 (Box 16:788)
    - Map of Springfield, Massachusetts, undated (Box 16:789)
    - Balance sheets and accounting data, 1949-1952 (Box 16:790)